hello and welcome to the 11th tutorial
on how to program in G script 2 so let's
open our level editor and I'm going to
show you one last variable it's the
level do variable so let's make a level
do variable called boat and make it
equal to Yellow just so yellow doesn't
feel left out now level. variables are
variables that are attached to the level
and all the NPCs in the level will be
affected by it these variables can be
changed client side or server
side
now it's sort of like client variables
and client R variables are attached to
the player and server R variables are
attached to the server and these
variables are attached to the
level
and this this. variables are attached to
the
NPC so all the variables are sort of
attached to something so except for like
temp which is just no temp is attached
to the function but anyway this is
level. Bo is equal the
yellow let's create a new NPC
here
oh
so basically this level that variable is
going to be created
here and then this NPC as soon as you
say something it's going to say the
level that boat variable which is yellow
so let's upload
that
hi now the invisible NPC says
yellow now there's one more thing I want
to cover before this tutorial ends that
is that there are some variables that
are
pre-made and by that I mean variables
that you can't use for anything else
other than what they're made for
examples of this are this do
chat this. chat is the is a variable is
a variable it is a variable of of the
players chat or an NPC's
chat or
text
also like something like this do green
this do red or this
do uh
blue blue uh blue would not be allowed
you would not be able to create them
because these are pre-made
variables so anyway there's a few other
variables that are already pre that are
also pre-made so if you ever create a
variable and it doesn't seem to work
just try to try to rename the variable
because it's possible that that variable
is pre-made and it won't let
you use it for anything else but what
it's used for so that concludes this
tutorial and I'll see you guys next time
uh bye